OK.
Hi.
嗨
Let's finish up.
咱们结束吧
This is from last lecture.
这是上一堂课的内容
I was going to talk about higher-order functions.
我原本要讲高阶函数的
Then I ran out of time.
然后我没时间了
So let's finish it.
咱们结束它
So maybe from CS62 and CS88, whatever class you're from, maybe you remember the idea of a higher-order function, which is a function that takes in another function as data.
也许你从CS62和CS88或者其他课上还记得高阶函数的概念 它是接受另一个函数作为数据的函数
So here's a little example in Python.
这里有一个简单的Python示例
Maybe I have a function called 10x.
也许我有一个叫做tenX的函数
It takes in a number and returns 10 times the number.
它接受一个数字并返回该数字的10倍
OK, great.
很好
Maybe I have another function called doTwice.
也许我有另一个叫做doTwice的函数
And this function takes in a number, but it also takes in a function.
这个函数接受一个数字 但它还接受一个函数
So the data itself is not like a number or a walrus, but it's the function itself.
数据本身不像一个数字或海象 但它是函数本身
And the thing I'm going to return is that function applied to that function applied to x.
我要返回的东西就是将x应用于该函数的函数
And so then I could say something like, Python, please print for me the result of doing twice the 10x function on the number 2.
我可以说 Python 请帮我计算一下TenX函数在数字2上的结果
And what would that be?
那将是什么呢
Well, I'd compute f of 2.
我将计算f的2
So 10 times 2 is 20.
10乘以2是20
And then I use f again on the result.
然后我再次使用f在结果上
And f of 20, that's 200.
f 的 20 就是 200
So that's the idea of the higher-order function.
这就是高阶函数的概念
Instead of just passing in numbers or strings, we're now passing in functions as data.
我们现在不仅传递数字或字符串 还传递函数作为数据
So the question for you, then, is how do we do this in Java?
那么 你的问题是 我们如何在 Java 中做到这一点
So in modern Java, there are some fancier ways to do this.
在现代的 Java 中 有一些更高级的方法来做到这一点
But the way that we have to learn it right now is kind of the old school Java way, mainly because this is what we'll see in the next lecture.
但是我们现在必须学习的方法还是有点老派的 Java 方法 主要是因为这是我们下一堂课要看到的内容
The fundamental problem, at least in older school Java, is that there's no such type.
至少在旧式 Java 中 根本问题是没有这样的类型
Remember in Java, every variable has to have a type.
记住在Java中 每个变量都必须有一个类型
So I could say int x. That's great.
我可以说Int x 那太棒了
But at least in older versions of Java, there's no way to say that f has type function.
但至少在较旧版本的Java中 没有办法说f有函数类型
That's not really a type.
那不是真正的类型
Nowadays it is, but in the older days, this memory box could not contain the address of another function.
现在它是 但在旧时代 这个内存盒不能包含另一个函数的地址
So we had to do something a little bit hacky, where we're going to take the function and somehow wrap it inside a class.
我们必须做一些有点巧妙的事情 我们要把这个函数包装到一个类里面
We know Java is super object-oriented.
我们知道Java是超级面向对象的
It loves objects.
它喜欢对象
So let's create an object that represents the function, and let's pass that object around.
那么让我们创建一个表示函数的对象 并将该对象传递
So what does this look like?
那么这是什么样子呢
Well, let's jump in and see what it looks like live.
好吧 让我们跳进去看看实际的样子
So here I am in my higher-order function demo.
我在我的高阶函数演示中
So what I will do is I'll first state, OK, well, there are a lot of functions that I could pass in.
那么我要做的是首先说明 好吧 有很多函数我可以传递
So maybe I'll create an interface to represent all the possible functions I could do.
也许我会创建一个接口来表示我可以做的所有可能的函数
So remember, in the previous example, we had 10x.
记住 在之前的例子中 我们有TenX
But I could have also had 11x.
但是我也可以有11x
I could have had.
我本可以有
x plus 5.
x + 5
I could have had all sorts of different operations.
我本可以有各种不同的操作
So to somehow represent all the possible functions I can pass in, I'm going to create an interface, and I'll call it int unary function.
为了表示我可以传入的所有可能函数 我将创建一个接口 并将其称为 整数一元函数
And this will be an object that represents a function.
这将是一个表示函数的对象
And what does this function do?
这个函数是做什么的
It takes in a single integer and returns an integer.
它接受一个整数并返回一个整数
So what does an int unary function object have to be able to do?
那么一个整数一元函数对象必须能做什么
Well, since it represents the function, we'd better be able to take in an integer and return the integer.
因为它代表函数 我们最好能够接受一个整数并返回一个整数
So I'll say something like public int apply int x. So it takes in an integer, returns an integer.
我会说像是 public int apply(int x) 这样的东西 所以它接受一个整数 返回一个整数
So this object somehow represents the set of all possible functions I could possibly pass into my do twice method.
这个对象以某种方式代表我可能传递给我的 do twice 方法的所有可能函数的集合
OK, great.
很棒
But I don't just want any unitary function in my doTwice method.
但是我不只是想要在我的do twice方法中有任何单一功能
Do you remember in the demo, I specifically wanted the 10x function?
你还记得在演示中 我特别想要10倍函数吗
So let's write the 10x function.
那么我们来写10倍函数吧
So I'll say public class 10x.
我会说public class_TenX
And 10x, it's not just any sort of object.
而且TenX 它不只是任何一种对象
It's actually a specific int unitary function.
它实际上是一个特定的Int单元函数
So I can say it implements. Int unary function.
我可以说它实现整数一元函数
It's one of those functions that takes in one number, outputs another number.
就是那种输入一个数字 输出另一个数字的函数之一
And here it's complaining.
而这里它在抱怨
It says, you claim to be an int unary function.
它说 你声称是一个整数一元函数
So therefore, you must be able to have this apply method.
你必须能够有这个apply方法
So I'll say, OK, I'm going to overwrite.
我会说 我要覆盖
That's not what I wanted.
这不是我想要的
I'm going to overwrite the apply method.
我要重写apply方法
How do I know I'm overriding?
我怎么知道我在重写呢
It's the exact same signature, and the override tag reminds me.
它的签名完全一样 而且override标记提醒了我
And what does 10x do?
那TenX是干什么用的
Returns 10 times x. OK, looks good to me.
返回10倍的x 看起来没问题
These two files, so far what we've written is, wherever my slides are, the equivalent of just this line right here, the 10x function.
这两个文件 到目前为止我们写的是 无论我的幻灯片在哪里 都相当于这里的这一行代码 即TenX函数
So first we have to specify this interface that says there are lots of different functions I could use.
首先我们必须指定这个接口 它表示我可以使用很多不同的函数
Then I specified one of those functions, the one that I want right now, it's called 10x.
然后我指定了其中一个函数 就是我现在想要的那个 它叫做 TenX
And it has this apply method that returns 10 times x.
它有一个 apply 方法 返回 10 倍 x
OK, now let's write the do twice section.
现在让我们来写 do twice 部分
So I'm going to skip back, and I'm going to start writing my do twice method.
我要跳回去 然后开始写我的 do twice 方法
So what should that look like?
那么这应该是什么样子
Well, it should return an integer, because I want to return the result of doing twice.
它应该返回一个整数 因为我想要返回两次执行的结果
And it's supposed to take in an integer.
并且它应该接收一个整数作为参数
But remember, it's supposed to also take in a function.
但记住 它还应该接受一个函数
So what type should the function be?
那么函数的类型应该是什么
I have to have a type here.
我必须在这里指定一个类型
Java expects a type.
Java期望有一个类型
So the type I'm going to use, because I don't always want to do 10x twice, I'm actually going to use int unary function.
我要使用的类型 因为我不总是想要两次执行10倍 实际上我要使用整数一元函数
That's the memory box type I'm going to use.
那就是我要使用的内存盒类型
And that's going to represent the fact that I could pass in any function that implements int unary function.
这将表示我可以传入任何实现整数一元函数的函数
And if it implements int unary function, we know it's got that apply method, so we're good.
如果它实现了整数一元函数 我们知道它有那个apply方法 所以一切都好
OK.
So what's the result?
那结果是什么
You might be tempted to write f of f of x, just like the Python example.
你可能会被诱导写成f的f的x 就像Python的例子一样
But remember, f is an object.
但要记住 f是一个对象
So you have to be a little bit more careful.
你要小心一点
You have to say f dot apply and get the method inside the object.
你必须说f dot apply并获取对象内部的方法
So it's f dot apply of f dot apply of x.
这是f点应用f点应用x
That looks pretty good.
看起来不错
So let's go try using this do twice method.
那么我们来试试使用这个do twice方法
So maybe I'll say result.
也许我会说结果
What should the result be?
结果应该是什么
Maybe I'll say I want the result of doing twice.
也许我会说我想要做两次的结果
And I want to do the 10x thing.
我想要做10倍的事情
And I want to do it on 2.
而且我想在2上做它
Maybe I'll print out the result.
也许我会打印出结果
We're pretty much there.
我们差不多到了
One final problem.
最后一个问题
This 10x, that's the name of the class.
这个TenX 那是类的名称
And it's expecting a specific instance of the class.
它期望类的特定实例
So I have to say new 10x.
我必须说new TenX
That's more trivia than something super fundamental to the whole demo.
这更像是一些琐事 而不是整个演示非常基本的东西
But basically, the idea is I can't just put the name of the class.
但基本上 这个想法是我不能只是放类的名字
I have to say, here's a 10x object.
我必须说 这是一个 TenX 对象
And the object has an apply method wrapped inside that this do twice method can call.
而这个对象里面有一个 apply 方法包裹在里面 这个 do twice 方法可以调用
So with all that, you'll notice Java's a little bit wordy.
通过所有这些 你会注意到 Java 有点啰嗦
I had to use three files to write this higher-order function demo.
我不得不使用三个文件来编写这个高阶函数演示
But eventually, I should hopefully get 200.
但最终 我应该希望达到 200
What did we learn?
我们学到了什么
We learned that while Java needs these two files to represent 10x, I have to say, this represents all the unary functions.
我们学到 虽然Java需要这两个文件来表示10倍 我必须说 这代表所有整数一元函数
It's like a new data type.
就像是一种新的数据类型
It represents all the unary functions.
它代表所有IntUnaryFunction(整数一元函数)
One of them, but not the only one, is 10x.
其中之一 但不是唯一的 是10倍
That's one of the unary functions out there.
那是其中一个存在的整数一元函数
And then when I wrote do twice, I could say, here's an int unary function object, which contains an apply method that's guaranteed from the interface.
然后当我写了两次do时 我可以说 这是一个整数一元函数对象 其中包含一个从接口中保证的apply方法
And I can call f.apply, f.apply of x.
而且我可以调用 f.apply f.apply 的 x
OK, thoughts, questions?
有什么想法 问题吗
Can I speak louder?
我能说得大声点吗
I can.
我可以
I can also try to hold this really close to my face.
我也可以尝试把这个靠得很近
OK, maybe I'll do that.
也许我会这样做
OK, thanks for bringing it up.
谢谢你提出来
Any other questions or requests?
有其他问题或请求吗
OK, I'm going to have to look goofy and just hold this to my face the whole time.
我只能看起来有点傻 一直把这个拿到我的脸前
OK, yeah, maybe there's a little volume control.
是的 可能有点音量控制
I don't know.
我不知道
OK, so just as a really quick side note, don't stare at the syntax too hard.
只是一个非常快的侧面说明 不要盯着语法看太久
In modern Java, so Java 8 or later, you actually now can have references to functions.
在现代的Java中 也就是Java 8或之后 你实际上现在可以拥有对函数的引用
But we won't teach them, because this general structure, where you pass objects around that have methods to represent higher-order functions, is going to come up in the next lecture, which is right now.
但我们不会教它们 因为在下一堂课中 也就是现在 会涉及到传递带有代表高阶函数的方法的对象的一般结构
So this is your last chance to ask questions
这是你最后提问的机会
Implementation inheritance, higher-order functions.
实现继承 高阶函数
I hope you enjoyed the demo.
希望你喜欢这个演示
OK, because there's more demos coming.
因为还有更多的演示要来
OK.
So now let's do this next lecture.
那么现在让我们进行下一讲
So today is all about some fancy thing called subtype polymorphism.
今天我们要讲的是一些被称为子类型多态性的花哨东西
What the heck is that?
这是什么鬼东西
So to break down the term a little bit, the word polymorphism, it means providing a single interface to entities of different types.
那么 简单解释一下这个术语 多态这个词的意思是为不同类型的实体提供一个统一的接口
A little mysterious.
有点神秘
So maybe we'll do an example to make it more clear.
也许我们可以举个例子来更清楚地说明
So remember, when you're building the deck, that's in project one.
记住 在构建甲板时 那是在项目一中
Well, what kind of deck is it?
那是什么样的甲板
You could build an array-based deck.
你可以建立一个基于数组的甲板
You could build a linkless-based deck.
你可以构建一个无链接的卡组
You could do some other kind of deck.
你也可以选择其他类型的卡组
It doesn't really matter.
这其实没什么关系
The deck is just some sequence of items with a front and a back.
卡组就是一系列带有前面和后面的项目
And you can add and remove from the front and the back.
你可以从前面和后面添加或删除
So if I have a deck object, I don't know what kind of deck object it is necessarily.
如果我有一个卡组对象 我不一定知道它是什么类型的卡组对象
But when I call add first, I can be confident that Java is going to call the correct
但当我调用add first时 我可以确信Java会调用正确的
At first method to do whatever it is the underlying deck needs to add an item.
首先 对于执行底层卡片需要添加项的方法
So if the underlying deck is a linked list deck and I call at first, I know there's going to be some weird little sentinel nodes being reassigned and the new node is going to be made.
如果底层卡片是链表卡片 并且我调用首先 我知道会有一些奇怪的小哨兵节点被重新分配 新节点会被创建
And I know that that's going to happen because this deck has type. BlinkListDeck.
而我知道这会发生是因为这个卡片有类型 BlinkListDeck
By contrast, if this deck just so happened to be an ArrayBasedDeck and I call that first,
相比之下 如果这个卡片碰巧是一个ArrayBasedDeck 并且我调用了首先
well then I trust that my ArrayBasedDeck object is going to somehow go into the array,
那么我相信我的ArrayBasedDeck对象会以某种方式进入数组
maybe do some resizing, and assign some of the indices to add first.
可能进行一些调整大小 并分配一些索引以添加第一个
So the idea here is you're going to rely on the object, going to trust the object.
这里的想法是你会依赖于对象 相信这个对象
Whatever this deck object is, is it a linkless deck?
不管这个卡片对象是什么 它是一个无链接的卡片吗
Is it an array-based deck?
这是基于数组的牌组吗
Is it some sort of other exotic deck?
这是某种其他奇特的牌组吗
Whatever object this is, you trust that it's going to do the right thing and call the proper at first method.
无论这是什么对象 你相信它会做正确的事情并调用正确的`at first`方法
And you might remember, sometimes we call that process of choosing the right method, dynamic method selection based on the dynamic type, like what actually is in this deck variable.
也许你还记得 有时我们称选择正确方法的过程为基于动态类型的动态方法选择 就像在这个牌组变量中实际上是什么一样
But that's subtype polymorphism.
但那是子类型多态性
The idea is, depending on what kind of deck this is, the at first can do different things.
这个想法是 取决于这是什么样的牌组 `at first`可以做不同的事情
And that's a good thing.
而这是一件好事
We like that, because we want this at first to do the right thing, depending on whether this is an array-based deck, linked list-based deck, other types of exotic decks.
我们喜欢这样 因为我们首先要做正确的事情 这取决于这是否是基于数组的牌组 基于链表的牌组 还是其他类型的奇特牌组
Great. So to contrast it a little bit with what other languages might do, some other languages might actually, instead of doing subtype polymorphism,
很好 所 以 为了与其他语言进行一些对比 一些其他语言实际上可能不使用子类型多态性
where we call out to the object and trust that it does the right thing, some other functions like Python,
我们在其中调用对象并信任它执行正确的操作
aScript likes doing this too, although we will not talk about it, is
一些其他语言（比如 Python 和我认为 JavaScript 也喜欢这样做 尽管我们不会讨论它）
They like explicitly passing in higher-order functions.
他们喜欢显式地传递高阶函数
So here's a little example.
这里有一个小例子
So in this example, we're going to do some Python-style programming.
在这个例子中 我们将进行一些Python风格的编程
And we're going to say, I want a method that prints out the larger of x and y. But what are x and y?
并且我们会说 我想要一个打印出x和y中较大者的方法 但是x和y是什么呢
They could be anything.
它们可以是任何东西
They could be numbers.
它们可以是数字
They could be strings.
它们可以是字符串
They could be, I don't know,
它们可能是 我不知道
Walruses, and I want to know which one is bigger.
海象 我想知道哪一个更大
So one way you can do that is you could say, here's x, here's y, and here is a custom-built compare function for whatever x and y are.
你可以这样做的一种方式是 你可以说 这是x 这是y 这是一个为x和y构建的自定义比较函数
If they are integers, here's a compare function that works on integers.
如果它们是整数 这是一个在整数上运行的比较函数
If they are dogs, here is a compare function that works on dogs.
如果它们是狗 这里有一个适用于狗的比较函数
And then you can call the compare function that was provided to you.
然后你可以调用给你提供的比较函数
So that would be something that you'd write in 61A, CS88, whatever other class.
这样的话 这将是你在61A、CS88或其他任何课程中写的内容
OK, by contrast, if you look at the subtype polymorphism approach, which is down here in this language, well, now it's a little bit different.
相比之下 如果你看一下这种语言中的子类型多态方法 那么现在情况就有点不同了
Now I'm passing an x and y. And instead of also passing in a custom built compare method,
现在我传递了一个x和y 而且我不再传递自定义的比较方法
I'm going to hope that the x object, whatever it is, dog, integer, string, I hope that this x object has a larger than method.
我希望这个x对象 无论是狗、整数、字符串 都有一个较大的方法
And I'm going to call out to the larger than method and hope that depending on what x is,
我将调用较大的方法 并希望根据x的数据类型 它的较大的方法能够正确地执行相应的操作
It's larger than method does the right thing for whatever data type x is.
它的较大方法是否针对x的数据类型做了正确的事情
So that's the main difference here. In the subtype polymorphism approach, we're letting the object do all the thinking for us.
这里的主要区别在于  在子类型多态性方法中 我们让对象为我们做所有的思考
This object is going to pick its own proper larger than method and use it for us, as opposed to here where we had to explicitly say, here's a compare method for you to use.
这个对象会选择适合自己的更大比较方法 并为我们使用 而不是像这里我们必须明确指出 这里有一个比较方法供你使用
OK.
So I know this is all kind of weird and philosophical.
我知道这一切听起来都有些奇怪和哲学化
So maybe let's get a little bit more concrete, and we'll try and build something together to see the power of subtype polymorphism.
或许我们该具体一点 一起尝试构建一些东西 以体会子类型多态的力量
So the big goal of today is to write a function called max.
今天的大目标是编写一个名为max的函数
Who is max, or what is max?
谁是max 或者什么是max
Well, it's a function that returns the max of any array.
它是一个返回任何数组的最大值的函数
regardless of what's in the array.
无论数组中是什么
So maybe I pass in an array of integers, and the max function should give me 7, because that's the largest integer.
也许我传入一个整数数组 最大函数应该给我7 因为那是最大的整数
Or I could pass in three dogs, Stuart, Elise, and Benjamin, and the max method should give me a reference to Benjamin, who is the largest of the three dogs.
或者我可以传入三只狗 Stuart、Elise和Benjamin 最大方法应该给我一个指向Benjamin的引用 因为他是这三只狗中最大的
So no matter what I pass in, I want my one true max function to always be able to give me the largest thing in the array,
无论我传入什么 我都希望我的唯一真正的最大函数始终能够给我数组中最大的东西
whether they are integers, or dogs, or strings, or something else entirely.
无论它们是整数、狗、字符串还是其他任何东西
So I've actually already tried to start write one for you.
我实际上已经试图开始为你写一个
So here it is.
这就是了
There's a function called max.
有一个叫做 max 的函数
You don't have to know exactly how it works.
你不需要确切知道它是如何工作的
But the kind of strategy I want to use here, and you can start thinking about if any of this seems broken, and I've even highlighted three places for you to consider,
但是我想要使用的策略 你可以开始思考一下这是否有问题 我甚至为你标出了三个地方让你考虑
the kind of idea, the little trick I want to use is I remember from last time, OK, you told me that everything extends object.
我想要使用的小技巧是我上次记得的 你告诉我说一切都扩展自对象
That's the idea in Java.
这是 Java 中的概念
Every single class is a subclass of object.
每个类都是对象的子类
So maybe, because I want my max object to support everything, integers, dogs, strings, I will actually allow it to take in an array of objects.
也许 因为我希望我的最大对象支持一切 整数 狗 字符串 我实际上会允许它接受一个对象数组
And I know that everything extends objects, so this is probably OK, unless this box is wrong.
我知道一切都扩展对象 所以这可能没问题 除非这个盒子有问题
And then I can compare all the items, and then don't worry too much about the for loop.
然后我可以比较所有的项目 然后不要太担心for循环
But it's basically comparing every item.
但基本上就是比较每个项目
If the ith item is greater than the biggest one I've seen so far, then I'll set my new best item, classic max stuff.
如果第i个项目大于我目前为止见过的最大值 那么我会设置我的新最佳项目 经典的max操作
And then later, I will call maximizer.max on my three dogs.
然后稍后 我会在我的三只狗上调用Maximizer.max
I'll cast it to a dog, and I'll send it to maxDog.
我会把它转换成狗 然后发送到maxDog
So the question for you is, are any of these problems that the compiler would yell about?
你的问题是 编译器会抱怨其中任何问题吗
So we can start to think about it.
那么我们可以开始考虑一下
We can ponder.
我们可以思考一下
We're a little bit short on time.
时间有点不够了
But OK, so kind of go through.
但好吧 就这样过一遍
Well, the first question is, does this little object trick work?
第一个问题是 这个小物体的技巧有效吗
Well, I think it does, because everything is an object.
我认为是的 因为一切都是对象
So a dog is an object.
一只狗就是一个对象
An integer is an object.
整数是一个对象
So no matter what I pass into this object,
无论我传递什么给这个对象
I think this line is OK.
我认为这行没问题
What about this line?
这行呢
What about this cast?
这个转换怎么样
What was that casting that I was talking about last time?
上次我提到的那个转换是什么
Well, remember, the cast doesn't actually change what the object is.
记住 转换实际上不会改变对象是什么
So when I call maximizer.max of dogs, I'm hoping to get Benjamin back.
当我调用 Maximizer.max 的 dogs 时 我希望得到 Benjamin
And when I cast to a dog, I am not changing anything about Benjamin.
当我把它转换成狗时 我对 Benjamin 没有任何改变
Benjamin is Benjamin.
Benjamin 就是 Benjamin
We're not going to go and change anything about this dog.
我们不会去改变这只狗的任何东西
However, by using this cast, we are telling Java, remember, the compiler is super cautious, and it only thinks about static types.
然而 通过使用这个转换 我们在告诉 Java 记住 编译器非常谨慎 它只考虑静态类型
So if the dog cast were not here, well, the compiler would think maximizer.max. What does that return?
如果这个狗转换不在这里 编译器会认为 Maximizer.max 返回什么
And it looks just the static type, compile time type, does not run the code.
而且它看起来只是静态类型 编译时类型 不运行代码
It says, ah, it returns object.
它说 它返回对象
I'm trying to assign an object into a memory box of type dog.
我试图将一个对象分配给一个狗类型的内存盒
Is an object a dog?
一个对象是狗吗
Sometimes, but not always.
有时候 但并不总是
Not all objects are dogs.
并不是所有的对象都是狗
So I'm not going to allow this.
我不会允许这样
However, by adding the cast, we're telling the compiler, don't be such a wimp.
然而 通过添加cast 我们在告诉编译器 不要如此懦弱
This is going to be a dog.
这将会是一个狗
Trust me.
相信我
I'm explicitly telling you.
我在明确地告诉你
You think it's an object based on the compile-time type.
你认为它是一个基于编译时类型的对象
I want you to secretly switch the compile-time type to dog, pretend it's a dog.
我想让你秘密地将编译时类型更改为狗 假装它是一只狗
And now the compiler is going to be, OK, you told me it's a dog.
现在编译器会说 你告诉我它是一只狗
I trust you.
我相信你
So I'm going to put this result into a memory box for dogs.
我要把这个结果放进狗的记忆盒子里
So it turns out this cast is OK.
原来这个石膏是可以的
It's actually the most natural place you'd use a cast.
其实这是你最自然会用石膏的地方
So that leaves this line.
那就留下这条线了
What do you think?
你觉得呢
Is it possible to say items i greater than items max-deck?
能不能说项目 i 大于项目 max-deck
Well, at first, it's very tempting to say, yeah, it seems totally fine.
一开始 诱人地说 是的 这似乎完全没问题
But the question for you is, how is the greater-than operator going to know how to compare the two dogs?
但对你来说 关键问题是 大于运算符如何知道如何比较这两只狗呢
How is it going to know I want to compare on size and maybe not, like, I don't know, the name?
它怎么知道我想按大小比较 而不是 比如说 名字
Or maybe the dogs have other attributes, how furry they are.
或者这两只狗可能有其他属性 比如它们有多毛
How does this greater than operator know what to do with the objects?
这个大于运算符怎么知道对这些对象该做什么呢
And it turns out, that is the problem.
问题就在这里
If I pass in two objects of any type, how could this greater than operator possibly understand how to compare the objects?
如果我传入两个任意类型的对象 这个大于运算符怎么可能理解如何比较这些对象呢
Maybe you want to compare the dogs based on name.
也许你想根据名字比较狗
Maybe you want to compare them on size.
也许你想根据大小比较它们
Maybe you want to compare them on fluffiness.
也许你想根据蓬松程度比较它们
I don't know.
我不知道
But there's all sorts of different ways you can compare objects.
但有各种不同的方式可以比较对象
This greater than operator just does not know.
这个大于运算符就是不知道
So we've got to fix this.
我们得修复这个
So how do we fix it?
那我们该怎么办呢
One thing we could do is we could go and say, hmm, this object thing is seeming kind of dicey.
我们可以尝试一种方法 就是去看看 这个对象的情况似乎有点不太好
I don't know.
我不知道
So maybe I'll just go and write a max function specific for dogs.
也许我可以写一个专门针对狗的最大函数
Well, now I can do specific things like if d.size greater than maxDog.size.
那么现在我可以做一些具体的事情 比如如果 d.size 大于 maxDog.size
Don't start the code too hard.
不要把代码写得太难了
But if I have a dog-specific method, that's great.
但如果我有一个针对狗的特定方法 那就太好了
Now I can do specific things like check the dog sizes.
现在我可以做一些具体的事情 比如检查狗的尺寸
But if we do this, we've kind of
但是如果我们这样做 我们有点
Given up on our dream of writing the one true max function.
放弃了我们编写唯一的最大函数的梦想
Because what if later the cats come along and I want a max cat method, or a max octopus method, or a max toucan method?
因为如果以后猫也来了 我想要一个最大猫的方法 或者一个最大章鱼的方法 或者一个最大巨嘴鸟的方法呢
I don't know.
我不知道
Well then, I'm going to have to copy paste this code over and over again.
那么 我就不得不一遍又一遍地复制粘贴这段代码
And I'm going to have to write a different max method for every single possible animal, or class, or object that I want to create.
我将不得不为每一个可能的动物、类别或对象编写一个不同的最大方法
And that's just kind of tedious.
而且这有点乏味
I want a one true max function that works for any kind of object I could ever possibly pass in.
我想要一个真正的最大函数 可以适用于我可能传入的任何类型的对象
So while this works, it's kind of clumsy.
虽然这样做有效 但有点笨拙
And I want to use that subtype polymorphism stuff to come up with a cleaner solution.
我想利用子类型多态性来找出一个更干净的解决方案
So that's what I'm going to do next.
接下来我要做的就是这样
So that's my problem.
这就是我的问题
Any questions or thoughts on our first try, where the problem is, and how we're going to try and use inheritance to solve it?
对我们的第一次尝试有任何问题或想法 问题在哪里 以及我们将如何尝试使用继承来解决它
So let's go and solve it.
那么让我们去解决它
So the way I'm going to solve it is I'm going to say, well, not all objects can be compared.
那么我打算这样解决它 我会说 并不是所有的对象都可以比较
So maybe there are some objects out there like, let's say, I don't know, images.
也许有一些对象 比如说 我不知道 图像
Maybe there's no obvious way to take two images and say which one's greater.
也许没有明显的方法来比较两个图像 看哪一个更大
Maybe there is.
也许有
But somehow we have to specify that dog is one of those things that can be compared.
但是我们必须以某种方式指定狗是可以比较的其中之一
So how do we do that?
那么我们怎么做呢
Well, let's go write an interface.
让我们写一个接口
It's kind of similar to the higher order function, int unary function thing we just did.
这有点类似于我们刚刚做的高阶函数、整数一元函数的东西
So we're going to write an interface.
我们要写一个接口
Then we're going to have Dog implement the interface.
然后我们会让 Dog 实现这个接口
Then we're going to write the Maximizer class using the interface.
接着我们会使用这个接口来编写 Maximizer 类
I know that sounds mysterious, so let's start coding some stuff, see if it makes any sense.
我知道听起来有点神秘 所以让我们开始编写一些代码 看看是否有意义
So I'm going to say, well, putting an object here is kind of scary, because I don't know how to compare objects with the greater than operator.
我要说 把一个对象放在这里有点吓人 因为我不知道如何使用大于运算符比较对象
So I'm going to say, I'm going to focus on a specific
我要说 我要专注于一个特定的
category of objects.
对象类别
Not all objects, but maybe I just want the objects that can be compared.
不是所有的对象 但也许我只想要可以进行比较的对象
So I'll create an interface saying, this interface represents the set of all objects that could possibly be compared.
我会创建一个接口 表示这个接口代表可能进行比较的所有对象的集合
And I'll call it our comparable.
我会称之为可比较
OK.
So if an object has to be able to be compared, what methods does it need?
如果一个对象必须能够被比较 它需要什么方法呢
Well, I think it needs one maybe like this.
我觉得它可能需要一个 也许像这样
So maybe I'll say compare to another object.
也许我会说与另一个对象比较
So if an object claims to be an R comparable, it says, I claim that I can be compared, then it had better have a method that allows us to compare it to some other object.
如果一个对象声称自己是可比较的 它说 我声称我可以被比较 那么它最好有一个方法允许我们将其与其他对象比较
OK.
Hmm.
嗯
Why does it say int?
为什么它说 int
Well, here's the documentation I'll write that will maybe make the int clear.
这是我将写的文档 也许会让 Int 变得清晰
Oh, autocomplete.
自动完成
OK.
So I'll say something like returns negative 1 if I, the current object, am less than O. OK.
我会说一些像如果我 当前对象 小于 O 就返回负 1 这样的东西
Returns 0 if I am equal to O. And maybe you already guessed the ending to this.
如果我等于 O 则返回 0 也许你已经猜到结尾了
Returns 1 if I am greater than O. OK.
如果我大于 O 则返回 1
So that's what this method needs to do.
这就是这个方法需要做的事情
So anybody who claims to be an R comparable must implement this method.
任何声称自己是 OurComparable的人都必须实现这个方法
They're going to inherit this method signature.
他们将继承这个方法签名
They must overwrite it, implement this method.
他们必须重写它 实现这个方法
And tell me, how do you compare this object to other objects?
告诉我 你如何将这个对象与其他对象进行比较
So now we go into dog.
现在我们进入狗
This is our favorite dog class from last time.
这是我们上次最喜欢的狗类
And I'm going to say, you know what?
我要说 你知道吗
This dog is not just any object.
这只狗不仅仅是任何对象
It's actually specifically an r-comparable object.
其实它是一个具体的可比较对象
It's an object that can be compared to other objects.
它是一个可以与其他对象比较的对象
Now it's complaining.
现在在抱怨
It says, you claim to be an r-comparable, so you'd better overwrite this compareTo method.
它说 你声称是一个可比较的对象 那你最好覆盖这个compareTo方法
So let's do what it says.
那么就按照它说的做吧
So override compareTo.
所以覆盖compareTo
And again, where did I get this method signature from?
再次 我从哪里得到这个方法签名的
Look, it's the same.
看 它是一样的
I copied it.
我复制了它
So I'm going to override.
我要覆盖
And well, how do I compare dogs?
那么 我该怎么比较狗呢
Well, maybe I'll say, if my size is less than the other dog's size, I'll return negative 1.
也许我会说 如果我的尺寸小于另一只狗的尺寸 我会返回负1
Otherwise, if my size is the same as the other dog's size, I'll return 0.
否则 如果我的尺寸和另一只狗的尺寸相同 我会返回0
And if my size is greater than the other dog's size, I'll return 1.
如果我的尺寸大于另一只狗的尺寸 我会返回1
Seems pretty good, but it's complaining.
看起来还不错 但它在抱怨
Why is it complaining?
为什么在抱怨
Cannot resolve symbol size.
无法解析符号大小
What does this mean?
这是什么意思
This is a type object.
这是一个类型对象
And remember, the Java compiler is super, super cautious.
记住 Java编译器非常、非常谨慎
And it just thinks about the static types.
它只考虑静态类型
So this is declared as an object.
这被声明为一个对象
And the Java compiler thinks, do objects have sizes?
而Java编译器会想 对象有大小吗
Well, sometimes, but not always.
有时候 但并不总是
Size was defined for a dog, some objects.
为狗定义了大小 一些对象
They don't have sizes.
它们没有大小
So it turns out.
所以结果是
Well, I can't just say dot size.
我不能只说点大小
But you and I both know we're pretty sure this is a dog, right?
但你和我都知道 我们都相当确定这是一只狗 对吧
If someone's asking to compare, I think this is a dog.
如果有人要求比较 我觉得这是一只狗
So you know what?
你知道吗
Java compiler, don't be so scared.
Java编译器 别那么害怕
I think this is really a dog.
我觉得这真的是一只狗
So I'm going to say, you know what?
我要说 你知道吗
I'm going to cast.
我要进行类型转换
So I'm going to say, it's the same dog.
我要说 这是同一只狗
I have not modified this dog in any way.
我没有以任何方式修改这只狗
I am just telling the compiler, please don't do your job for this moment.
我只是告诉编译器 请暂时不要执行你的工作
Instead of saying, oh, I'm going to say other dog,
不是说 噢 我要说其他的狗
And this is the exact same object.
这就是完全相同的对象
It just now has static type dog, because we trust that this is a dog.
它现在只是具有静态类型的狗 因为我们相信这是一只狗
And Java now says, OK, well, if you're telling me it's a dog, then I trust you.
而Java现在说 如果你告诉我它是一只狗 那么我就相信你
And it has a size method.
它有一个大小方法
OK.
Great.
太棒了
Question?
问题
The question was, do you want to cast it in the arguments?
问题是 你想要在参数中转换它吗
Do you want to cast it here?
你想在这里转换它吗
Well, if you put it here, there's a little problem, which it says, you're no longer overwriting.
如果你把它放在这里 会有一个小问题 它说 你不再覆盖
Here, it was object.
这里 它是对象
Here, you put dog.
在这里 你放狗
That's no good.
那不行
OK.
That's a great question, though.
这是个很棒的问题 不过
OK, so we're almost there.
我们快到了
Seems like a lot of work.
感觉好像很多工作
But we first declared, here is the interface that represents all objects that can be compared.
但是我们首先声明 这里是表示可以进行比较的所有对象的接口
One of those objects is dogs.
其中一个对象是狗
There could be others, like cats, octopuses, whatever else I said.
可能还有其他的 比如猫、章鱼 无论我说了什么
Now, finally, we're back in the Maximizer class.
现在 最后 我们回到了Maximizer类
And what's in the Maximizer?
而Maximizer类中有什么
Well, now is no longer the case that I want to take the max of any object.
现在不再是我想要获取任何对象的最大值了
But I'm going to specifically narrow this down to all the r comparables in the world.
而是我要将其具体缩小到世界上所有可比较的r
So you need to give me some array of r comparables.
你需要给我一些OurComparable的数组
And how do I compare the two r comparables?
那么我如何比较这两个OurComparable的对象
Well, I could say.
我可以说
Items i dot compareTo items maxStack.
items[i].compareTo(items[maxDex]
And what allows me to use this?
什么让我可以使用这个
Why is Java so confident?
为什么Java这么自信
And why am I so confident that this object will have a compareTo method?
为什么我这么确信这个对象会有一个compareTo方法
Because this object is an R comparable, and we just made the rule.
因为这个对象是一个可比较的 R 而我们刚刚制定了规则
If you're an R comparable, you've got to have this.
如果你是一个可比较的 R 你就得拥有这个
So Java is OK with this.
所以 Java 对这个没问题
I'm OK with this.
我对这个没问题
I am confident that this is an R comparable.
我确信这是一个可比较的 R
It's got to have the compareTo.
它必须有 compareTo
So what is this number?
那么这个数字是什么
Well, if the number is greater than 0, that means I'm greater than O, so I should change the maxDex.
好吧 如果数量大于0 那意味着我比O大 所以我应该更改maxDex
OK.
Great.
太棒了
After all that work, we created the new interface of all the comparable things.
经过那么多工作 我们创建了所有可比较事物的新界面
We said dog is one of those things.
我们说狗是其中之一
And now Maximizer doesn't just take in any object, but takes in specifically those objects that have a compareTo method.
现在最大化器不仅接受任何对象 而是专门接受那些具有compareTo方法的对象
So back to our little demo, I have Elise, 3, Steward, 9, Benjamin, 15.
回到我们的小演示 我有Elise 3 Steward 9 Benjamin 15
I'm going to call the Maximizer.
我要给最大化器打电话
And hopefully, the largest dog says, bark.
希望最大的狗说 汪汪
Benjamin says, bark.
本杰明说 汪汪
It seems like something worked.
似乎有点儿灵验
OK, reflection time, question time.
反思时间 问题时间
OK, that's not the slides I want.
那不是我想要的幻灯片
Where did the slides I want go?
我想要的幻灯片去哪儿了
OK, sorry, too many tabs.
抱歉 标签太多了
That's also not the slides I want.
这也不是我想要的幻灯片
OK, there it is.
就是这个
So that's our game plan.
这就是我们的游戏计划
That's what we ended up doing.
这就是我们最终做的事情
So we first said, this is the R comparable interface.
我们首先说 这是R可比接口
OK, great.
太棒了
And then we said, dog is a specific type of R comparable.
然后我们说 狗是一种特定类型的OurComparable的
Remember, we had to use the little cast to say, this object, we know it's a dog.
记住 我们必须使用小写字母来说 这个对象 我们知道它是一只狗
Java, please trust me.
Java 请相信我
It's really a dog.
真的是一只狗
And then the maximizer could take in the R comparables instead of any sort of objects.
然后最大化器可以接受OurComparable而不是任何对象
And that's good, because we are guaranteeing that any r-comparable objects must have that compared-to method.
这很好 因为我们保证任何OurComparable的对象都必须具有比较方法
OK, questions, thoughts, before I make one little tweak?
好了 有问题、想法 还是在我做一点微调之前
Yeah?
是吗
The question was, can you implement more than one interface?
问题是 你能实现多个接口吗
I believe you can.
我相信你可以的
I'm not going to do it now, because I don't have enough interfaces.
我现在不打算这么做 因为我没有足够的接口
But you could if you wanted to.
但如果你愿意 你是可以的
implements lists.
实现列表
I don't think dogs are lists, but I guess you could.
我不认为狗是列表 但我猜你可以的
It lets you do it.
它让你这样做
It doesn't complain if I say dog is a list.
如果我说狗是一个列表 它不会抱怨
It just gets confused.
它只是感到困惑
Other questions, thoughts?
其他问题 想法
Great, so one little thing I will do, by the way, this is good as is, if you want to leave it like this, all is well.
太好了 还有一件小事我要做 顺便说一句 如果你想保留它 一切都好
But one little improvement I will notice is this code, it's kind of long.
但我要注意一点改进就是这段代码 有点长
It barely fits in my beautiful high-contrast IntelliJ, which, by the way, I spent like the last week using this.
它几乎装不下我漂亮的高对比度的IntelliJ 顺便说一句 我上周花了好几天用这个
I got to say, it's kind of growing on me.
我得说 这有点让我感兴趣
But I don't know about you.
但我不知道你呢
OK, maybe you should try it in your projects.
好吧 也许你应该在你的项目中试试它
Anyway, OK, where was I?
不管怎样 我在哪儿
So this code, it's kind of long.
这段代码 有点长
I feel like this three if cases for something as simple as comparing sizes is kind of long.
我觉得为了像比较大小这么简单的事情而使用三个if语句有点长
So here's a little shortcut I'm going to use that real Java often uses.
这里有一个我要用的小技巧 真正的Java经常使用
Instead of doing all this if case, negative 1, 0, 1 thing, I'm going to return this dot size minus other dog dot size.
不要做所有这些 if case、负 1、0、1 这些东西 我会返回这个点的大小减去其他狗的大小
And why would I do this?
那我为什么要这样做呢
Well, if I look at this.
好吧 如果我看一下这个
Hm.
So this means that if I am less than the other dog, this number is going to be negative, because I'm less than the other dog.
这意味着如果我比另一个狗小 这个数字将是负数 因为我比另一个狗小
If I'm equal to the other dog's size, this will return 0.
如果我和另一个狗的大小相等 这将返回 0
If I'm bigger than the other dog, this will return greater than 0.
如果我比另一个狗大 这将返回大于 0
So it turns out this works perfectly fine as well.
原来这也完全正常工作
The only difference is here I need to change my documentation a little bit.
唯一的区别是这里我需要稍微修改一下我的文档
And I have to return not just negative 1, but just any negative number if I'm less than 0, and any positive number if I'm greater than 0.
而且如果我小于0 我不仅需要返回-1 而是任何负数 如果我大于0 我需要返回任何正数
It's OK if you don't have to necessarily see this and say, oh, this is so much better than what we had before.
如果你不一定要看到这一点然后说 哦 这比我们以前的好多了 那也没关系
But it's a nice little shortcut that it turns out real Java programmers use.
但这是一个很好的小技巧 原来真正的Java程序员都在用
So I find it kind of nice.
我觉得挺好的
OK.
Great.
太棒了
So that was the final little improvement we made.
那就是我们做的最后一点小改进
And it's just to make the code a little bit shorter.
只是为了让代码变得更短一点
I don't actually know why Josh uses otadog instead of otherdog.
我其实不知道为什么Josh使用otadog而不是其他狗
But if you're curious, he has a link.
但如果你好奇的话 他有一个链接
So check it out.
去看看吧
OK.
Something in Hawaii.
在夏威夷的一些事情
Yeah, I've never been, so I cannot claim.
是的 我从未去过 所以我不能声称
OK, so what does this mean?
那这意味着什么
What does this take away from all this coding that we've done?
这从我们所做的所有编码中带走了什么
Well, we've achieved our dream of writing the one true max function.
我们实现了编写唯一的最大函数的梦想
It's amazing, because now I have this maximizer.max function, and any comparables that I possibly throw at it
真是令人惊奇 因为现在我有了这个Maximizer.max函数 任何我可能投入其中的可比较物品
It can compare them using the compareTo method and give me the largest item.
它可以使用compareTo方法进行比较 并给我最大的项目
That's amazing.
太厉害了
It doesn't matter what is inside this sumfile.txt.
sumfile.txt里面是什么无所谓
It could be dogs.
可能是狗
It could be strings.
也可能是字符串
It could be, I don't know, Hawaiian pups or whatever.
可能是 我不知道 夏威夷的小狗或其他什么
I don't know what he's doing in Hawaii, but OK.
我不知道他在夏威夷干什么 但没问题
And so whatever I pass in, the maximizer.max function will compare them and give me the maximum so long as those items implement are comparable.
因此 无论我传入什么 Maximizer.max函数都会比较它们并给我最大值 只要这些项实现了可比较性
That's amazing.
太棒了
So well, what's the problem with that?
那有什么问题呢
Is this good yet?
这样行吗
There's a little puzzle here in the interest of time, because we spent time doing the higher-order function.
出于时间考虑 我们花时间做高阶函数 所以这里有点小难题
I'll leave this to you to try it, but it's kind of interesting.
我就把这个留给你来尝试吧 但这挺有意思的
It's a cool little puzzle, so do try it out.
这是一个很酷的小难题 所以一定要试试看
There's the spoiler.
这就是剧透
Don't read it yet.
现在不要读
OK, so there are two problems with this that I don't really like.
所以这有两个问题我不太喜欢
So one of the problems is I don't really like this cast.
其中一个问题是我不太喜欢这个演员阵容
It's just kind of gross.
这有点恶心
We know that cats can be kind of dangerous, because if this object is not a dog, and you try to say, Java, please treat this cat like a dog, Java will say, no, I can't do that, and the program will crash.
我们知道猫有点危险 因为如果这个物体不是狗 而你尝试说 Java 请把这只猫当作狗对待 Java会说 不 我不能这样做 程序会崩溃
So I don't really like this cast.
我不太喜欢这个演员阵容
It's kind of dangerous.
有点危险
So I want to be able to get rid of that if I can.
如果可能的话 我想要摆脱那个
But the second problem, which is a bit more fundamental, is remember how we said, hey, we achieved our one true dream of the max method.
但第二个问题 稍微更根本的是 记住我们说过的 嘿 我们实现了我们唯一的梦想 即最大方法
And now it's like, anything I pass in, I can take the max, as long as it implements r comparable.
现在就像 我传入任何东西 我都可以取最大值 只要它实现了OurComparable
That's amazing.
那太棒了
So what is the list of all things that implements r comparable?
那么所有实现OurComparable的东西列表是什么
Well, there's dog.
有dog
And there's, oh wait, there's only dog.
还有 哦等等 只有dog
There's the only thing that has implemented R comparable so far.
到目前为止 唯一实现了OurComparable的东西就是这个了
Why is that?
为什么呢
Because we just made it up like 10 minutes ago.
因为我们就是大概十分钟前才想出来的
So one problem with using R comparable is that in the real world, there's nothing that implements R comparable except dog.
使用OurComparable的一个问题是 在现实世界中 除了狗之外 没有任何东西实现了OurComparable
So this method, while it's perfect,
虽然这个方法很完美
For all the things that are R-comparables, there are no such things that are R-comparables yet, except dog.
对于所有的OurComparable的东西来说 除了狗之外 没有其他的OurComparable的东西
So unless you intend to go out and rewrite the entire Java standard library so that all these other things, integers and strings and arrays, implement R-comparable, then this method is not going to be very general purpose.
除非你打算去重写整个Java标准库 让所有这些其他的东西 整数、字符串和数组 都实现OurComparable 否则这个方法将不会非常通用
And again, the reason is because we made up R Comparable.
再次 原因是因为我们编造了OurComparable
The only R Comparable that exists in the world right now that implements R Comparable is Dog, and there's nothing else.
现在世界上唯一实现OurComparable 的 OurComparable 就是 Dog 别无他物
So how do I make this better?
那么我该怎么做得更好呢
Well, it turns out that instead of using our little made-up R Comparable, we can actually use the real one.
事实证明 我们不必使用我们编造的小 OurComparable 实际上我们可以使用真正的 OurComparable
Java has its own interface called Comparable, and it's built into Java.
Java 有自己的接口叫做 Comparable 并且它内置在 Java 中
And what's great about this is everybody knows about this.
最棒的是 每个人都知道这个
You and I now know about it.
你和我现在也知道了
All the other people learning Java know about this.
其他学习Java的人都知道这个
Everyone else writing Java knows about Comparable.
其他编写Java的人都知道Comparable
And this is great.
这很棒
This means that if anyone else comes up with a brand new class, it probably has already implemented Comparable.
这意味着如果有人提出一个全新的类 它很可能已经实现了Comparable
Or if there's some other class you care about, like integers or strings, it probably already implements Comparable.
或者如果你关心的是某个其他类 比如整数或字符串 它们很可能已经实现了Comparable
So instead of using this R comparable made-up thing, let's go use the real one
与其使用这个虚构的OurComparable 不如去使用真正的Comparable
so we can be in line with all the other Java programmers in the world.
这样我们就能和世界上所有其他的Java程序员保持一致
And the other nice little thing is that here, while the compareTo take took an object, and I had to cast it, and it was gross,
另一个好处是 在这里 compareTo方法接受一个对象 我不得不进行类型转换 这很糟糕
here the comparable takes in a generic type, and that will save us a little cast.
而这里的Comparable接受一个泛型类型 这会让我们少做一些类型转换
It's kind of like a little syntax trick, so don't stare at it too hard.
有点像一个小语法技巧 不要盯着看太久
But it turns out it's pretty nice.
但事实证明这挺不错的
OK, so R comparable, it was great, but I'm done playing with you because you are too specific to us.
好吧 所以 OurComparable 这很棒 但我不想再和你玩了 因为你对我们来说太具体了
We made it up.
我们凭空捏造的
I want to use the general purpose one.
我想要使用通用的
So instead of saying you're an R comparable, I'm going to say you're a comparable.
不是说你是一个 OurComparable 我要说你是一个可比较的
It's built into Java, and it takes in a generic type.
它内置在 Java 中 并且接受一个通用类型
I'm going to pick dog.
我要挑狗
All this is saying is it's comparable of dogs.
这只是在说它可以与狗相比
So I can compare myself to what?
我可以拿自己来比较什么
To other dogs.
与其他狗比较
Now the override tag is complaining.
现在重写标签在抱怨
It says, well, now you're no longer comparing to an object.
它说 好吧 现在你不再是在比较一个对象了
If I look back at the method signature, wherever it is, you see how it says, here, I have a placeholder T. And then here, I have a placeholder T. These two need to match.
如果我回头看方法签名 在哪里 你看到它是这样说的 这里 我有一个占位符 T 然后这里 我有一个占位符 T 这两个需要匹配
So in my code.
在我的代码里
This object type, it needs to match the placeholder.
这个对象类型 它需要匹配占位符
So now this is dog.
现在这是狗
And that's great.
而且这很棒
That means it saves us this little cast.
这意味着它为我们节省了这个小转换
This item is already a dog.
这个项目已经是一个狗了
So I can maybe just call it other dog.
我可能只需要称它为另一个狗
And so that saves me a little cast.
这就为我省了一点点成本
It's like a little sleight of hand in Java.
就像 Java 中的一点点手法
So it's kind of nice.
感觉还不错
But the important thing is that now this comparable, we are matching with everything else that the Java developers are doing.
但重要的是现在这个可比较 我们正在与 Java 开发者做的一切其他事情进行匹配
So in the real world, tons of things are already comparables.
在现实世界中 已经有大量的可比较的东西了
It's not like our comparable where we made it up and there was only a dog that was comparable.
不像我们自己编的那个可比较 那时只有一只狗是可比较的
OK.
And everything else mostly works.
而其他大部分都正常运行
I can run it again just to show you.
我可以再次运行它 只是为了向你展示
And now we are plugged into the rest of the Java libraries and the rest of the Java community.
现在我们已经连接到其余的Java库和Java社区
Everyone knows how to use comparables, so we're all good.
每个人都知道如何使用可比较对象 我们都很好
We don't have to manually implement tons and tons of R comparables.
我们不必手动实现大量的OurComparable对象
OK.
Benjamin still says bark.
本杰明还是会叫的
That's good.
这很好
OK.
Sorry for all the tapping.
抱歉一直在敲击
I am a total mess today.
今天我一团糟
OK, so here's a picture of what actually happened.
这就是实际发生的事情的图片
So initially, we said, dog is an R comparable.
最初我们说 狗是可比较的 R
That's great.
太棒了
But nothing else in the world is an R comparable.
但世界上没有其他东西可以与之相媲美
The dog is the only R comparable ever.
狗是迄今为止唯一可与之相媲美的R
However, if I say that dog is a comparable, well, that's great, because all sorts of other things in the world are comparable already.
然而 如果我说狗是可比的 那真是太棒了 因为世界上已经有各种各样可比的东西了
So I like this a lot better.
我更喜欢这个
This means that I can use different library functions.
这意味着我可以使用不同的库函数
And it turns out, like, Max is already written for us.
事实证明 像Max这样的函数已经为我们编写好了
So there's already a method called max in the collections library that takes in comparables and gives you the largest item.
在集合库中已经有一个叫做max的方法 它接受可比的参数并给你最大的项
And there's also min, there's median, all sorts of great things.
还有最小值 还有中位数 各种好东西
And then the second little benefit we saw is that because it takes in this little placeholder type, I don't have to say object here.
然后我们看到的第二个小好处是 因为它接受了这种小占位符类型 我这里不用说对象
I can just say dog, and that's kind of nice too.
我可以直接说狗 这也挺好的
So that was my last fix, just to make us in line with real Java as opposed to making up comparables ourselves.
这就是我的最后修复 只是为了使我们与真正的Java保持一致 而不是自己编造可比性
Any thoughts before I go on to the final topic?
在我继续最后一个话题之前 有什么想法吗
OK.
So continuing on with our theme of comparing dogs, well, there's one little problem, which I kind of hinted at earlier.
继续我们比较狗的主题 有一个小问题 我之前有点暗示过
Maybe you spotted it.
也许你已经注意到了
Well, there's a little problem, which is, I guess I'll start by telling you the term natural order,
有一个小问题 我想我会先告诉你自然顺序这个术语
which is, if you call the compareTo method over and over and over again on all the dogs in the world,
如果你在世界上所有的狗身上反复调用compareTo方法
and you can line them up in some order using the compareTo method, that resulting order is called natural order.
并且你可以使用compareTo方法将它们按某种顺序排列 那么得到的顺序就被称为自然顺序
So for example, if I took all my dogs from before, and I lined them up, and I used the compareTo method to see who's greater, I would get all the dogs in order by size.
例如 如果我拿出之前所有的狗 然后排成一排 用compareTo方法看谁更大 我会得到所有狗按大小排列的顺序
That's their natural order.
那就是它们的自然顺序
But the problem is, well, I guess here's an example.
但问题是 我想这里有一个例子
OK, so in this slide, we have Doge, size 5.
在这张幻灯片上 我们有Doge 大小为5
That's the smallest.
那是最小的
And we have Grigometh, interesting dog, of size 200.
我们还有 Grigometh 一只有趣的狗 大小为 200
And then we have Clifford, copyright, of size 9,000.
然后我们有 Clifford 版权 大小为 9,000
OK, great.
太好了
But that's not the only way we could sort these dogs, right?
但这不是我们可以排序这些狗的唯一方式 对吧
I look at these dogs, and I'm like, well, I don't know.
我看着这些狗 就觉得 我不知道
Maybe they're in a classroom or something, and I want to sort them alphabetically.
也许它们在教室里之类的地方 我想按字母顺序对它们排序
Well, that's not alphabetical order.
那不是按字母顺序
So maybe there's another way I could sort these dogs that's not the natural order.
也许有另一种方法可以对这些狗进行排序 不是按照自然顺序
So maybe, just maybe, later down the line, I'm like, I don't want to put these dogs in order and compare them by size.
也许 也许 过一段时间 我会觉得 我不想按大小比较这些狗 也不想按顺序排列它们
I actually want to put them in order by name.
我实际上想按照名字的顺序排列它们
I want to have Clifford come first, because C is earlier in the alphabet.
我希望首先是 Clifford 因为 C 在字母表中靠前
Then I want to have Doge next.
然后我想下一个是 Doge
And then this hideous Grigometh is the last one, because G is last in the alphabet of these three words.
然后 这个丑陋的 Grigometh 是最后一个 因为在这三个单词的字母表中 G 是最后一个
OK.
OK, you are too scary.
好吧 你太可怕了
Go away, Gregor.
走开 Gregor
OK, so how would we do this in Java, based on everything we've seen so far?
那么根据我们迄今所见的一切 我们该如何在Java中做到这一点呢
Well, first, just to give you a baseline for comparison, how would I do this in the higher-order function approach?
首先 只是为了给你一个比较的基准 我该如何在高阶函数方法中做到这一点呢
Well, all I'd have to do, remember this approach from before?
我所要做的就是 还记得之前的方法吗
where I take in the objects, and I also take in a custom-built compare method for that specific object.
在那个方法中 我接收对象 并且还接收一个针对该特定对象的自定义比较方法
Well, then all I have to do is, instead of passing in a method that compares their sizes, I can just pass in a different method or a different function that compares their names instead.
那么 我所要做的就是 不是传递一个比较它们大小的方法 而是传递一个比较它们名称的不同方法或不同函数
Or I could compare their fluffiness.
或者我可以比较它们的蓬松程度
Or I could compare, I don't know, how likely they are to come and haunt my dreams.
或者我可以比较 我不知道 它们来侵扰我的梦的可能性有多大
OK.
But I can do all sorts of different comparisons just by passing in different compare methods.
但我可以通过传入不同的比较方法来进行各种不同的比较
So how do I do this with subtype polymorphism?
那么我如何使用子类型多态性呢
That's going to be your question to think about, because now I'm trying to call, you know, the X objects larger than method
这将是你需要考虑的问题 因为现在我正在尝试调用X对象的larger than方法
and hope that X has the right larger than method to use, but I don't have this extra option to pass in different compare functions.
并希望X有正确的larger than方法可供使用 但我没有这个额外的选项来传入不同的比较函数
So this approach suddenly, hmm, doesn't seem like there's an easy fix.
这种方法突然间 似乎没有简单的解决办法
You could maybe think of some exotic fixes.
你或许可以考虑一些奇特的解决方案
Maybe, I don't know, there's like a larger than 2, and then the second larger than compares in a different way.
也许 我不知道 有一个大于2的 然后第二个大于以不同的方式进行比较
Maybe there's like a method inside this object called larger than 3.
也许在这个对象内部有一个叫做大于3的方法
You could do that, and maybe there's some documentation that tells you which ones they are.
你可以这样做 也许有一些文档告诉你它们是哪些
So maybe something like that.
也许有类似的东西
Maybe you've taken a string, and then it checks the string to tell you which compare to use.
也许你已经拿到了一个字符串 然后它会检查这个字符串告诉你应该使用哪种比较方式
So those approaches, while they might work, they're ultimately not what Java settled on.
这些方法虽然可能有效 但最终不是 Java 采用的方式
Here are some examples.
这里有一些例子
And ultimately, what the Java developer settled on is something kind of like the higher-order functions from before, and I find it pretty cool.
最终 Java 开发者采用的方法有点像以前的高阶函数 我觉得挺酷的
So let's try it out.
那我们来试试吧
So the subtype polymorphism approach is we're actually going to pass in a function just like the higher-order function approach.
因此 子类型多态的方法是 我们实际上会像高阶函数那样传入一个函数
But remember that in old-school Java, you cannot actually pass in a function.
但请记住 在老式的 Java 中 你实际上是不能传入一个函数的
So we're going to have to pass in the function wrapped inside a class.
我们得将函数封装在一个类内传递
Just like how we saw that 10x function was wrapped inside a class and the intunary interface was wrapped inside a class, we're going to pass in a function to compare x and y wrapped inside a class.
就像我们看到的那个 TenX 函数被封装在一个类内 三元接口也被封装在一个类内一样 我们将传入一个比较 x 和 y 的函数 也封装在一个类内
OK.
Seems kind of weird.
感觉有点奇怪
Let's try it out.
让我们试试看
So I'm going to go and implement a new comparator that compares things by size.
我要去实现一个新的比较器 通过大小比较事物
OK, so here I go.
现在开始
So before, we already had dogs.
以前我们已经有狗了
Dogs know how to compare themselves to other dogs.
狗知道如何与其他狗比较
They use their size.
它们利用自己的大小
But what if I want to compare them using name?
但如果我想用名字来比较它们呢
Well, now this dog, it's out of ways to compare, right?
好吧 现在这只狗 它已经无法再比较了 对吧
This dog has run out of tricks.
这只狗已经没有更多的招数了
I cannot teach it any more tricks.
我不能再教它任何新的技巧
There is a single compareTo method.
有一个单独的compareTo方法
You cannot have compareTo 3, compareTo 4, compareTo 5.
你不能有compareTo 3 compareTo 4 compareTo 5
The dog simply cannot learn that many tricks.
狗根本就学不会那么多花招
So instead, I'm going to build a new class.
我要构建一个新的类
This is something new.
这是全新的东西
And I'm going to say public class NameComparator.
我会说public class NameComparator
And if you think of classes or objects as representing things in the real world, for example, the dog class represents a dog,
如果你将类或对象看作是代表现实世界中的事物 例如 dog类代表一只狗
Then I would say, and maybe this dog learns tricks and compared to is one of the tricks.
那我会说 也许这只狗会学一些技巧 与之相比就是其中一种技巧
I would say name comparator, what it is.
我会说名字比较器 它是什么
Think of it like the dog comparing machine.
把它想象成狗比较机
So I will say implements comparator.
我会说实现比较器
The word's a little bit different.
这个词有点不同
This is no longer an object that can compare itself to other objects.
这不再是一个可以将自己与其他对象进行比较的对象
This is like a machine that takes in objects and compares them for you.
这就像一个接受对象并为你比较它们的机器
So I'll say implements comparator of dog.
我会说实现狗的比较器
It's complaining.
它在抱怨
I have to import something.
我得导入一些东西
OK, great.
太棒了
So now it's complaining.
现在它在抱怨
It says, you claim to be a dog.
它说 你声称自己是一只狗
Oh, that's a lot of words.
哦 这是很多字
You claim to be a dog comparing machine.
你声称是一台狗比较机器
So you need to tell me how to compare.
你需要告诉我如何比较
So actually, I'll use this little trick you used in the project.
实际上 我会使用你在项目中使用的这个小技巧
And I'll say, OK, what do I need to implement and override?
然后我会说 我需要实现和覆盖什么
Aha, I need to override this method, compare.
啊哈 我需要覆盖这个方法 compare
So let's do it.
那么我们就这么做吧
I want to be able to use the names to compare O1 and O2.
我想要能够使用这些名称来比较 o1 和 o2
There are two dogs.
有两只狗
This is the dog comparing machine.
这是比狗的机器
It comes with a method.
它带有一种方法
It's like a button you can press.
就像你可以按的按钮一样
You can take in two dogs, press the Compare button, and it will tell you which one is greater based on the name.
你可以带进两只狗 按下比较按钮 它会告诉你根据名字哪个更大
So how would I do that?
那我该怎么做呢
Well, I know I have O1's name.
我知道我有o1的名字
I know I have O2's name.
我知道我有o2的名字
I could try and loop through and check the strings and see who comes later in the alphabet.
我可以尝试循环遍历并检查字符串 看看谁在字母表中出现得更晚
But instead, I'm going to realize strings are comparable.
但我打算意识到字符串是可以比较的
So I'll just cheat a little bit and use the string objects compareTo method.
我会稍微作弊一下 使用字符串对象的compareTo方法
So I'll say, O1.name, you're a string.
我会说 o1.name 你是一个字符串
Please compare yourself to the second dog's name and tell me who's greater and return the integer.
请与第二只狗的名字比较自己 告诉我谁更大并返回整数
So I've built a dog comparing machine.
我建了一个狗比较机
And why did I have to do this?
为什么我要做这个
Because the original dog, it already had its natural order compare-to method.
因为原始的狗 它已经有了自己的自然顺序比较方法
It could not learn any more compare-to methods.
它不能学习更多的比较方法
We ran out.
我们用完了
So we had to build a new separate dog comparing machine that takes in two dogs and tells me which one's bigger.
我们不得不建立一个新的独立的狗比较机 它接受两只狗 告诉我哪个更大
And this category of comparison machines, it's the interface comparator.
而这种比较机器的类别 它是接口比较器
And as we saw on the slides, I tabbed the wrong way again.
正如我们在幻灯片上看到的 我又一次点击了错误的方式
Sorry.
抱歉
If we look on the slides, this comparator interface, it has just a single method you have to override, namely compare.
如果我们看幻灯片 这个比较器接口 它只有一个方法你需要覆盖 即比较
You need to tell me how to compare two objects.
你需要告诉我如何比较两个对象
OK.
Excellent.
太棒了
Let's go try using it.
让我们尝试使用它
So I will go into maximizer.java.
我会进入Maximizer.java
So I need some dogs to do my experiment.
我需要一些狗来做我的实验
Do I have time to solicit?
我有时间来征求吗
OK.
Even if I don't have time, I want to do it.
即使我没有时间 我也想做
So I need two dogs to feed into my hopefully humane, will not harm animals, dog comparison machine.
我需要两只狗喂入我的希望是人道的、不会伤害动物的狗比较机器
Who would like to volunteer their creature?
谁愿意志愿他们的动物
Nobody?
没有人
Anyone on Zoom want to volunteer their creature?
Zoom上有人愿意自愿提供他们的宠物吗
So many people wanted to give up their animals last semester.
上个学期有很多人想要放弃他们的动物
Mr. Snuffles.
斯纳夫尔先生
All right, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
等一下 等一下 等一下 等一下
That's too many.
那太多了
OK.
We're also going to need their size.
我们还需要知道它们的大小
So OK, OK, OK.
Oski.
Oski
Give me one.
给我一个
Oski?
Oski
I don't think Oski's a dog, but OK.
我不认为Oski是只狗 但好吧
And what's the size of Oski?
那么Oski的尺寸是多少
I don't know.
我不知道
200.
200?
OK.
I don't even know what units those are.
我甚至不知道那些是什么单位
OK.
Like that?
像那样吗
OK, what's the size?
尺寸是多少
OK, I don't think these are dogs, but OK.
我不认为这些是狗 但
Sorry, what is it?
抱歉 这是什么
OK, I am not entirely clear that these are dogs, but I guess.
我不是完全清楚这些是狗 但我猜
OK, but I guess neither was Grigometh.
但我猜格里戈梅斯也不是
So OK, no negative sizes.
没有负数尺寸
It's too much.
太多了
OK, so here are two creatures that we will pretend are dogs.
这里有两个我们假装是狗的生物
And we're going to try and ask the dog comparing machine, who is greater?
我们要试着问问狗比较机 谁更厉害
So I'll say, well, I guess I'll use a comparison.
我会说 好吧 我猜我会用一个比较
It returns an integer.
它返回一个整数
I want to call this compare method.
我想调用这个比较方法
Except I don't have it yet.
除了我还没有它
I need to create and instantiate a NameComparator class first.
我需要先创建和实例化一个 NameComparator 类
So I'll say NameComparator equals new NameComparator.
我会说 NameComparator nc = new NameComparator()
All I'm doing is I'm creating a new instance of this object.
我所做的就是创建这个对象的一个新实例
Now that I have a new instance of this object, I can say NC.
既然我有了这个对象的新实例 我可以说 nc
This is like me grabbing the name comparison machine.
这就像我抓住了名字比较机一样
I've created one from scratch.
我是从零开始创建的一个
And now that I have the machine, I can call compare on it.
既然我有了这台机器 我就可以调用它的比较功能
And I can shove in the two dogs.
然后我可以把这两只狗塞进去
They seem very heavy, but I'll do it.
它们看起来很重 但我会做到的
So I'll pass in d4.
那我会传入d4
I will pass in d5.
我会传入d5
And they will return a number to me.
然后他们会给我返回一个数字
And if the number is greater than 0, that tells me that d4 comes later in the alphabet.
如果数字大于0 那告诉我d4在字母表中排在d5后面
So then I will have d4 make its hideous noise.
那么我就让d4发出它可怕的噪音
And then otherwise, I will have d5 make its hideous noise.
否则 我会让d5发出它可怕的噪音
OK, great.
太棒了
So this would indicate that D5 comes later in the alphabet.
这表明d5在字母表中排在后面
OK, so I'm still caught up.
我还在卡住
I forgot who comes later.
我忘了谁排在后面了
OK, I think ASCII comes later than syllabus because O comes later in the alphabet than C. So hopefully, we get, what do we get?
我认为ASCII比syllabus晚因为O在字母表中比C晚 希望我们会得到 我们得到了什么
We get?
我们得到了什么
OK, Benjamin says bark, so the size comparison is still working.
本杰明说bark 所以大小比较还有效
But now we have an extra feature, thanks to this comparison machine.
但现在我们有了一个额外的功能 多亏了这个比较机器
So I built the comparison machine.
我建造了比较机器
I shoved in my two new creatures.
我把我的两个新生物塞了进去
And it tells me that Oski says bark, because, well, Oski comes later in the alphabet in Syrabus.
然后它告诉我 Oski说bark 因为Oski在Syrabus字母表中排在后面
Does Oski actually say bark at events and stuff?
Oski在活动和其他事情中真的会叫吗
I don't know.
我不知道
OK, next time you see Oski, next time you see Oski, you should pet.
下次你见到Oski 下次你见到Oski 你应该摸摸它
Maybe it'll bark.
也许它会叫
OK, great.
太好了
So that was our name comparator.
这是我们的名称比较器
At this point, if you're satisfied with all this code that I've written, then maybe this next section will be a little bit trivia.
到了这一步 如果你对我写的所有这些代码感到满意 那么也许下一节会有一点小知识点
But it turns out this works perfectly fine.
但事实证明这完全没问题
The only little gripe I have with it is that this is not what comparators really look like in real Java code.
我唯一的小抱怨是这并不是实际 Java 代码中比较器的真实样子
So I'm going to make a series of small changes just to make this look like real Java code.
我会做一系列小改动 使其看起来像真实的 Java 代码
But I will warn you, it's a little bit technical.
但我要提醒你 这有点技术性
And I'm not actually changing the fundamentals.
而且我实际上并没有改变基本原理
So there's still going to be a name comparison machine that takes in two dogs and compares them by name and is different from the original comparison, which was comparing by size.
仍然会有一个名字比较机器 接收两只狗的名字并按名字进行比较 与原始比较不同 原始比较是按大小比较
So I'm not changing anything about the comparator.
我并没有改变比较器的任何内容
I am just making it look like what real people do in Java.
我只是让它看起来像真正的Java代码
And if you're totally lost by now, it's OK if this part is lost on you.
如果你现在完全迷失了 如果你对这部分迷失了 那没关系
It's not the most interesting part.
这不是最有趣的部分
But we want to make this look like real Java code so we can impress our friends.
但我们想让这看起来像真正的Java代码 这样我们就可以给我们的朋友留下深刻印象
So let's do that.
那我们就这么做吧
So the first observation I'll notice is this NameComparator, it doesn't have to be its own class.
那么我首先注意到的是这个NameComparator 它不必是一个独立的类
Right now, I have to distribute Dog to the world, and I have to distribute NameComparator?
现在 我必须把Dog分发给世界 还要分发NameComparator吗
That's a little bit annoying.
这有点烦人
So instead, I'm going to take this and say, just kind of like the node in the S list, I'm going to say, NameComparator, you're not a standalone class.
我打算这样做 就像S列表中的节点一样 我会说 NameComparator 你不是一个独立的类
I think you're like a feature of Dog.
我认为你是Dog的一个特性
So instead of distributing two files, now I can distribute one.
现在我只需分发一个文件 而不是两个
Then I can say, name comparator, you're like a subordinate feature of Dog.
那么我可以说 名称比较器 你就像狗的一个从属功能
That's really what you are.
这真的是你的本质
So I can take this class.
我可以使用这个类
I can nest it inside.
我可以把它嵌套在里面
And that really has not changed anything about the code itself.
而且这实际上并没有改变代码本身的任何内容
It's the same code.
它还是同样的代码
I simply moved it to a different file.
我只是将它移到了一个不同的文件中
OK.
Improvement number two, that's not obvious, which is name comparator.
第二项改进 那不太明显 就是名字比较器
Is this a thing that all dogs have?
这是所有狗都有的东西吗
All dogs have a size.
所有狗都有一个大小
All dogs have a name.
所有狗都有一个名字
Is it the case that every dog has a separate name comparator?
是每只狗都有一个单独的名字比较器吗
Because if so, then I have to say something like, well, I want, like, Oski, go get me a name comparator.
因为如果是这样的话 那我必须说一些像 我想要 像 Oski 去给我找一个名字比较器
Like, Oski, fetch.
喜欢 Oski 去获取
And then he gets a name comparator.
然后他得到了一个名字比较器
That's kind of weird.
这有点奇怪
I don't know if individual dogs have name comparators.
我不知道单个狗是否有名字比较器
I feel a lot better if NameComparator is an attribute of the whole class.
如果NameComparator是整个类的属性 我会感觉好多了
Do you remember ScientificName from, like, Lecture 2?
你还记得 像 第二讲的ScientificName吗
That was static, because all dogs have the same scientific name.
那是静态的 因为所有的狗都有相同的科学名字
So I think all dogs have the same NameComparator.
我觉得所有的狗都有相同的NameComparator
It's not like Oskie has its own little machine, and then Cerebus has its own little machine.
不像Oskie有自己的小机器 然后Cerebus有自己的小机器
Seems like everyone is using the same NameComparator machine, so I will make this static.
似乎每个人都在使用相同的NameComparator机器 所以我会将其设为静态的
Again, not a super obvious improvement, but one I decided to make.
再次强调 这不是一个非常明显的改进 但我决定做出这个改变
And the benefit of that is instead of saying, like, OSCE, go fetch a name comparator.
而其中的好处是 不再需要说像Oskie那样去获取一个名字比较器
That's kind of weird.
有点奇怪
I can now say dog.nameComparator because it's static.
我现在可以说dog.nameComparator因为它是静态的
And I think that looks pretty nice.
我觉得这看起来相当不错
OK.
So again, you don't have to look at this and say, ah, this is so much better.
再说一遍 你不必看着这个说 啊 这好多了
The thing before was so gross.
之前那个太恶心了
This is just what the people who write Java tend to do.
这只是那些写Java的人倾向于做的事情
OK.
So again, this works perfectly fine if you're happy with it.
再说一遍 如果你对此感到满意 这完全没问题
Go run with it.
拿去跑吧
I'll make one final little change, again, just to reflect what people in Java do, which is I'm going to make this class private, which at first seems weird.
我会做一个最后的小改动 再次 只是为了反映Java中的做法 我会将这个类设为私有的 起初似乎有点奇怪
Hmm.
Suddenly, the outside world cannot access NameComparator.
突然间 外部世界无法访问NameComparator
But instead of letting them access this raw class directly, I'm going to give them a method to access the class.
但我不会让它们直接访问这个原始类 我会给它们一个访问该类的方法
So I will say public static comparator of dog get NameComparator.
我会说public static comparator <dog> getNameComparator
And I'll just have this return new NameComparator.
然后我只需让它返回new NameComparator
So instead of asking the outside world to create the object, I'll give them a method that does it for them.
不是要求外界创建对象 我会给他们一个方法来做这件事
So now I can no longer call new outside, but I can call dog.getNameComparator.
现在我不能再外部调用 new 了 但我可以调用 dog.getNameComparator
That's great.
太好了
And now NameComparator is private, so I cannot use that type in the outside world.
现在 NameComparator 是私有的 所以我不能在外部世界中使用那个类型
I need a memory box that can hold NameComparison machines.
我需要一个可以容纳 NameComparison 机器的内存盒
What variable type could I use to hold NameComparators?
我可以用什么变量类型来容纳 NameComparators 呢
Well, I could use comparator of t.
我可以使用 t 的比较器
Because I know that all name comparators are comparators.
因为我知道所有的名称比较器都是比较器
OK.
Great.
太棒了
And I guess I have to import that, too.
我猜我也得导入那个
And again, it's OK.
而且 这也没问题
You don't have to look at this and say, wow, this is so much better.
你不必看着这个说 哇 这好太多了
The thing you showed me before was so gross.
你之前给我看的那个东西太恶心了
This is really the same code as before when we had name comparator in a different file.
这真的和之前我们在另一个文件中有名称比较器的代码一样
This is just me making some tiny little changes and moving the files around a little bit just to make it look like what real Java programmers tend to do.
这只是我做了一些微小的改动 并稍微移动了文件 以使其看起来像真正的Java程序员倾向于做的那样
So now, again, I have Benjamin says bark, and I have Aski says maybe sort of.
现在 我再次让Benjamin说汪汪 还有Oski说可能吧
Maybe it says bark.
可能它说汪
OK.
Great.
太好了
Here's the hierarchy that we built.
这是我们构建的层次结构
At this point, it is really tempting to somehow link all the classes that we made.
现在 真的很诱人地想要以某种方式链接我们创建的所有类
And remember, you can build these diagrams where you say, dog is an animal.
记住 你可以构建这些图表 比如说 狗是一种动物
You can build a diagram with all the inheritance relationships.
你可以构建一个包含所有继承关系的图表
And at this point, it is so tempting, because you have seen something called comparator and comparable.
而且 现在 真的很诱人 因为你已经看到了一个叫做比较器和可比较的东西
It's so tempting to link them together.
把它们联系起来真的很诱人
But you have to be really careful, because a dog-comparing machine
但你必须非常小心 因为一个狗比较机器
It is not a dog.
不是一只狗
It's a dog comparing machine.
这是一台狗比较机器
So our name comparator, it's a comparator.
我们的名字比较器 它是一个比较器
It is not a dog.
它不是一只狗
There's no arrow between those.
它们之间没有箭头
And if you wanted to, you could build more comparators.
而且如果你想的话 你可以建造更多的比较器
You could build a size comparator.
你可以建造一个大小比较器
You could build a fluffiness comparator.
你可以建造一个蓬松度比较器
You could build a how likely are they to come haunt me in my dreams comparator.
你可以建立一个多大可能性他们会在我的梦中出现的比较器
Oski, that's you.
Oski 那就是你
OK.
So I could build all sorts of comparators.
我可以建立各种各样的比较器
And they would all implement this comparator interface.
它们都会实现这个比较器接口
But none of them are subclasses of dog.
但它们都不是 dog 的子类
And that's really one of those key things that people always get hung up on.
这真的是人们总是纠结的关键事情之一
What's the difference between a comparator and a dog?
比较器和狗有什么区别呢
Again, if you think of them as physical objects in the real world, in our little examples, you could say a dog, well, that's a thing that can compare itself to other objects.
再说一次 如果你把它们想象成现实世界中的物体 在我们的小例子中 你可以说狗 那是一种可以将自己与其他物体进行比较的东西
So the dogs, because they implement comparable, they learn a trick, which is they can compare themselves to other objects.
狗 因为它们实现了可比较性 它们学会了一个技巧 就是它们可以将自己与其他物体进行比较
So I can ask the dog, do your trick, and it will do a little trick and compare itself to other dogs.
我可以问狗 做你的把戏 它就会做一个小把戏 然后将自己与其他狗进行比较
By contrast, the comparators, those are not dogs at all.
相比之下 比较器 它们根本不是狗
They are these big dog comparing machines, and they implement comparator, which is the set of all machines that can compare things.
它们是这些大型狗比较机器 并且它们实现了比较器 这是可以比较事物的所有机器的集合
And so this happens to be a comparator of dogs.
这恰好是一个狗的比较器
But remember, a dog comparing machine is not a dog.
但请记住 狗比较机器不是一只狗
So maybe another more concise way of putting this, since I'm kind of rambling on this slide, a compareable is comparing yourself to other objects.
也许另一种更简洁的表达方式 因为我在这张幻灯片上有点絮絮叨叨 一个比较器是将自己与其他对象进行比较
The dog learns a trick, compares itself to other objects.
狗学会了一个技巧 将自己与其他对象进行比较
A comparateur is an object.
比较器是一个对象
It's not the dog.
这不是狗
It's just a machine that compares two separate objects.
它只是一个比较两个不同对象的机器
And we can see it here.
而且我们可以在这里看到
It's a compare method.
这是一个比较方法
It takes in two separate objects.
它接收两个单独的对象
So here's the example from before.
这是之前的例子
I guess in this case, they didn't bother to make it private.
我想在这种情况下 他们没有费心将其设置为私有的
But you could do that if you wanted to.
但如果你想的话 你可以这样做
Again, this works just the same as before.
同样 这与之前的操作完全相同
You can compare and then have the one with the larger name bark.
你可以进行比较 然后让名字更大的那个叫
OK.
Dang, I actually got through everything.
哎呀 我居然把所有事情都搞定了
That's nuts.
太疯狂了
OK.
Does anyone have final questions before I let you go?
在我放你们走之前 有没有最后的问题
OK.
I'll see you next time.
下次见
Go pet Oski and see if Oski barks and let me know what you think.
去抚摸Oski 看看Oski是否会叫 然后告诉我你的想法
OK.
Or go pet Cerebus and tell me if Cerebus barks or just consumes you.
或者去抚摸Cerebus 告诉我Cerebus是否会叫 还是只是消耗你
OK.
Enough from me. Bye.
我说的就这么多  再见
See you next time.
下次见